Register of the Gottfried Haberler papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence II, 1978-1991
  - From Schlesinger, Helmut to Gerald Ford, 1988 (Box-folder 58: 11)
  - From Zeiss, Raoul to Frederiecke Haberler, 1989 (Box-folder 58: 12)
  - Invitations, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 58: 13)
  - Aaron, Henry (Box-folder 58: 14)
  - Acham, Karl
  - Allen, Loring
  - American Austrian Foundation (Box-folder 58: 15-16)
  - Aultmon, Cleve (Box-folder 58: 17)
  - Austrian Embassy
  - Ayau, Manuel F.
  - Balassa, Bela
  - Baldwin, Robert
  - Balestrieri, Jean
  - Balthaser, Bob
  - Barfield, Claude
  - Bartley, William W., III
  - Beaud, Michel
  - Beltram, L.
  - Bergsten, C. Fred (Box-folder 58: 18)
  - Bhagwati, Jagdish (Box-folder 58: 19)
  - Billings, Arthur
  - Birnbaum, Eugene A.
  - Bloch, Lucille L.
  - Bolick, Robert
  - Boustani, Anthony
  - Böhm, Stephan
  - Briefs, Godfrey E.
  - Browne, Martha Steffy
  - Brunner, Karl
  - Buchanan, James
  - Burns, Joe
  - Butcher, Willard C.
  - Caldwell, Evelyn
  - Campbell, W. Glenn
  - Cass, Ronald A. (Box-folder 58: 20)
  - Chai, Michel
  - Chapin, Russell
  - Conference on Research in Income and Wealth
  - Czinkota, Michael R.
  - Dale, Edward
  - DeMuth, Christopher (Box-folder 59: 1)
  - Dole, Bob
  - Donges, Juergen B.
  - Dorfman, Robert
  - Dorn, James A.
  - Durand, Edith
  - Earle, Hobart
  - Earley, James
  - Eizenga, Wietze
  - Elzinga, Kenneth G. (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - Enzelsberber, Ernst F.
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Kansas City
  - Feldstein, Martin
  - Fischer, Stanley
  - Fisher, Joseph L.
  - Fong, Shan-Kwei
  - Frenkel, Jacob A.
  - Friedman, Milton
  - Gavin, Brigid
  - Giersch, Herbert
  - Goldstein, Morris
  - Griswold, Erwin N. (Box-folder 59: 3)
  - Gutowski, Armin
  - Haberler, Klaus
  - Hagemann, Harald
  - Hansen, Hans R.
  - Hanusch, Horst
  - Haraf, Bill
  - Hasse, Rolf
  - Hein, Werner
  - Heller, Robert H.
  - Henderson, Margaret
  - Henning, Rick
  - Hermans, Ferdinand
  - Hinshaw, Randall
  - Holzherr, Christian
  - Hofmann, Daniel M. (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - Hothreiter, Eduard
  - Hoxter, Curtis
  - Huber-Kuenzer, Elly
  - Hufbauer, Gary
  - Huggins, Gordon
  - Humphrey, Thomas M.
  - Husain, Ishrat
  - Internal Revenue Service
  - Irwin, Douglas
  - Johnson, Dorothy
  - Jöhn, Ernst (Box-folder 59: 5)
  - Junz, Helen B.
  - Kafka, Alexandre
  - Katz, Lora (Box-folder 59: 6)
  - Katz, Samuel I. (Box-folder 59: 7)
  - Kennen, Peter
  - Kindleberger, Charles P.
  - Klein, Philip A.
  - Knight, David
  - Koo, Anthony Y.C.
  - Koren, Stephan
  - Kosters, Marvin
  - Kurz, Rudi (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - Lal, Deepak
  - Lambsdorff, Otto, Graf
  - Leslie, John E.
  - Levy, Mickey
  - Liebeler, Susan
  - Livingston, R.G.
  - Löschner, Ernst
  - Lübbert, Jens I.
  - McCormick, Richard
  - McCracken, Paul W.
  - Machlup, Mitzi
  - Makin, John
  - Marshall, James N.
  - Martin, Frieda
  - Mathews, James, Bishop
  - Mayr, Walter
  - Mayrzedt, Hans
  - Miller, David Charles, Jr. (Box-folder 59: 9)
  - Mellor, William W., III
  - Molsberger, Josef
  - Munnell, Alicia H.
  - Müller-Groeling, Hubertus
  - National Bureau of Economic Research
  - National Security Political Action Committee
  - Negreponti-Delivanis, Maria
  - Niskanen, William
  - Nuzzo, James L. J.
  - Oberman, Kenneth J.
  - Okada, Mutsumi
  - Oppenheim, Daniel P.
  - Oppenheim, Elsie
  - Panas, Eustace (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Perlman, Mark
  - Pollack, Gerald A.
  - Prothro, Pam
  - Pu, Shan
  - Raffer, Kunibert
  - Ramírez, Rogelio
  - Rauch, Peter
  - Richter, Rudolf
  - Riedel, James
  - Rieger, Philipp
  - Robbins, John W.
  - Robbins, Kenneth
  - Robinson, Thomas W.
  - Rockwell, Llewellyn H.
  - Ronald Regan Presidential Foundation
  - Royal Bank of Scotland
  - Royal Economic Society
  - Rudenstine, Neil L.
  - Salant, Walter S.
  - Scheide, Joachim
  - Schilgerius, Silvia
  - Schlesinger, Helmut
  - Schulman, Horst (Box-folder 60: 2)
  - Seldon, Arthur
  - Seuss, Wilhelm
  - Shih, Chien-Sheng
  - Silverman, Dan P.
  - Simon, Julian L.
  - Socher, Karl
  - Solomon, Elinor
  - Somary, Wolfgang
  - Spillane, Annie
  - Stadler, Wilfred
  - Stein, Herbert
  - Steinbeisser, Michael (Box-folder 60: 3)
  - Stolper, Wolfgang
  - Straube, Kerstin (Box-folder 60: 4)
  - Styles, Ed
  - Sugioka, Michio
  - Swedeburg, Richard
  - Sweeny, Richard J.
  - Taquey, Charles H.
  - Theroux, David J.
  - Tien, Xiaoqing
  - Tlan, Edgar
  - Tomasson, Gunnar
  - Truman, Edwin M. (Box-folder 60: 5)
  - Tsui, Shu-hsiang
  - Wallich, Christine
  - Wallich, Mabel
  - Walker, Charls E.
  - Walter, Norbert
  - Walters, Alan
  - Watrin, Christian
  - Willett, Thomas
  - Winterberger, Gerhard
  - Zassenhaus, Herbert
  - Zimmer-Lehmann, Georg
  - Zeiss, Raoul
  - Zombanakis, Minos A.
  - Unidentified (Box-folder 60: 6)
- Speeches and Writings II, 1934-1989
  - Royalty statements, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 60: 7)
  - "Austria's Economic Development After Two World Wars: A Mirror Picture of the World Economy,", 1980 (Box-folder 60: 8)
  - "Critical Notes on Schumpeter's Theory of Money - The Doctrine of the 'Objective' Exchange of Money," drafts and related correspondence, 1985 (Box-folder 60: 9)
  - "Floating Rates Buoy the World Money System," with related correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 60: 10)
  - Letters to the Editor, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 61: 1)
  - "The Money Supply and the Trade Deficit," with related correspondence and printed matter, 1984 (Box-folder 61: 2)
  - "Mr. Keyne's Theory of the 'Multiplier': A Methodological Criticism,", circa 1960s (Box-folder 61: 3)
  - "Österreichs Wirtschaftliche Entwicklung nach den beiden Weltkriegen: Ein Spiegelbild der Weltwirtschaft,", 1980 (Box-folder 61: 4)
  - "Political Business Cycles"
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 61: 5)
  - "The Problem of Stagflation"
    - Proposed illustrative chart and back cover copy, 1985 (Box-folder 61: 6)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 61: 7-10)
    - "Final draft,", 1985 (Box-folder 61: 11)
    - Galley proofs, 1985 (Box-folder 61: 12)
  - "Recommended Policies for the Allied Military Government in Germany," draft, 1944 (Box-folder 61: 13)
  - "Selected Essays of Gottfried Haberler"
    - Correspondence and contractual documents, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 61: 14-16)
    - Book reviews and related correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 62: 1-2)
  - "Should Floating Continue?" galleys and related correspondence, 1988 (Box-folder 62: 3)
  - "Should Quotas Be Alien to Imports?" with related correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 62: 4)
  - "Systematic Analysis of the Theories of the Business Cycle," with related correspondence, 1934-1947 (Box-folder 62: 5)
  - "Theory of a Tool of Policy,", 1983 (Box-folder 62: 6)
  - "Wage and Price Rigidities, Supply Restrictions, and the Problem of Stagflation"
    - Manuscript contract, 1983 (Box-folder 62: 7)
    - Galleys and drafts, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 62: 8-10)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box-folder 62: 11)
    - Foreward by William J. Baroody, 1985 (Box-folder 62: 12)
  - William H. White obituary and related correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 62: 13)
  - General correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 62: 14)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1987-1988
    - Press releases and memoranda, circa 1980s (Box-folder 67: 6)
    - Meeting schedules, 1988 (Box-folder 67: 7)
    - Expense reports, 1987 (Box-folder 67: 8)
- Writings by Others II, 1959-1991
  - Annan, Noel, 1984 (Box-folder 62: 15)
  - Arndt, Sven W., 1987 (Box-folder 62: 16)
  - Bernstein, Edward M., 1991 (Box-folder 62: 18)
  - Böhm, Stephan, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 62: 19-21)
  - Bradley, Robert L., Jr., 1988 (Box-folder 62: 22)
  - Brahm, Heinz, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 62: 23)
  - Brems, Hans, 1984 (Box-folder 62: 24)
  - Brittan, Samuel, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Burns, Arthur F., 1984 (Box-folder 63: 2)
  - Brüggemann, Gerd, 1987 (Box-folder 63: 3)
  - Cline, William R., 1989 (Box-folder 63: 4)
  - Collins, Susan M., 1989 (Box-folder 63: 5)
  - Corden, Max, 1990 (Box-folder 63: 6)
  - Eichengreen, Barry, 1986 (Box-folder 63: 7)
  - Feldstein, Martin, 1984 (Box-folder 63: 7-8)
  - Fest, Joachim, 1984 (Box-folder 63: 10)
  - Frankel, Jeffrey A., 1987 (Box-folder 63: 11)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 63: 12-16)
  - Frenkel, Jacob A., 1989 (Box-folder 63: 17)
  - Furth, J. Herbert, 1988 (Box-folder 63: 18)
  - Galbraith, Kenneth John, 1984 (Box-folder 63: 19)
  - Georgescu-Roegen, N., 1988 (Box-folder 63: 20)
  - Giersch, Herbert, 1987 (Box-folder 63: 21)
  - Goldstein, Henry N., 1989 (Box-folder 63: 22)
  - Grossman, H.I., 1989 (Box-folder 63: 23)
  - Gutowski, Armin, 1988 (Box-folder 63: 24)
  - Hasse, Rolf E., 1988 (Box-folder 63: 25)
  - Heilbrunn, Jacob E., 1990 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Heller, Robert H., undated (Box-folder 64: 2)
  - Henderson, David, 1989 (Box-folder 64: 3)
  - Hermens, Ferdinand, 1974, 1989 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Hofmann, Daniel, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 64: 5-7)
  - Humphrey, Thomas M., 1988 (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Kaplan, J.J., circa 1980s (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - Keeton, Charles Lee, III, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Kenadjian, Berdj, undated (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - Kindleberger, Charles P., 1985-1989 (Box-folder 64: 12-14)
  - Kissinger, Henry, 1988 (Box-folder 64: 15)
  - Koenig, Peter, 1988 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  - Koo, Anthony Y.C., 1988 (Box-folder 64: 17)
  - Krugman, Paul R., 1988 (Box-folder 64: 18)
  - Lal, Deepak, 1988 (Box-folder 64: 19)
  - Leube, Kurt R., undated (Box-folder 64: 20)
  - Machlup, Fritz, 1985 (Box-folder 64: 21)
  - Maltsev, Yuri, circa 1990s (Box-folder 64: 22)
  - Marston, Richard C., circa 1980s (Box-folder 64: 23-24)
  - Meltzer, Allen H., circa 1980s (Box-folder 64: 25)
  - Musgrave, Richard A., 1991 (Box-folder 64: 26)
  - von Neumann Whitman, Marina, 1987 (Box-folder 64: 27)
  - Prebisch, Raul, 1959 (Box-folder 64: 28)
  - Ramirez, Rogelio, 1987 (Box-folder 64: 29)
  - Recktenwald, Horst Claus, 1988 (Box-folder 64: 30)
  - Samuelson, Paul A., 1991 (Box-folder 64: 31)
  - Scheide, Joachim, 1989 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - Schlesinger, Helmut, 1991 (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - Seldon, Arthur, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Seuss, Wilhelm, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 65: 4-6)
  - Silverman, Dan, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Skousen, Mark, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 8)
  - Socher, Karl, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 9-11)
  - Solomon, Elinor, 1991 (Box-folder 65: 12)
  - Srinivasan, T.N., 1990 (Box-folder 65: 13)
  - Stein, Herbert, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 14)
  - Sugioka, Michio, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 15)
  - Taquey, Charles H., 1990 (Box-folder 65: 16)
  - Truman, Edwin M., 1987 (Box-folder 65: 17)
  - Ungerer, Horst, 1984-1988 (Box-folder 65: 28)
  - Vanek, Jaroslav, 1986 (Box-folder 65: 18)
  - Vernon, Raymond, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 19)
  - Volker, Paul, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 20)
  - Wagner Tsukamoto, Sigmund, undated (Box-folder 65: 21)
  - Watrin, Christian, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 65: 22-23)
  - Willitt, Thomas, 1990 (Box-folder 65: 24)
  - Winterberg, Gerhard, 1987 (Box-folder 65: 25)
  - Wolf, Martin, 1988 (Box-folder 65: 26)
  - Zlowe, David, undated (Box-folder 65: 27)
  - Unidentified, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 66: 1-3, 67: 13)
- Printed Matter II, 1985-1991
  - "Appendix: Representativness of Firms in the Sample,", undated (Box-folder 66: 4)
  - The Cato Journal, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 5)
  - Critical newspaper advertisment endorsed by Haberler, 1988 (Box-folder 66: 6)
  - "The Economy at Midyear," report, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 7)
  - "Eleanor Lansing Dulles: 95 Years of Speaking Out,", 1988 (Box-folder 66: 8)
  - Eric Voegelin memorial articles, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 9)
  - Free University leaflet, undated (Box-folder 66: 10)
  - General newspaper clippings, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 66: 11)
  - Hayek, F.A. encyclopaedia entry, circa 1980s (Box-folder 66: 12)
  - Hayek, F.A. interview, 1985 (Box-folder 66: 13)
  - "Humane Studies Review,", 1988-1989 (Box-folder 66: 14)
  - Index to economics report, circa 1980s (Box-folder 66: 15)
  - International Center for Economic Growth publications list, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 16)
  - International Joseph A. Schumpeter Society member directories and newsletter, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 66: 17)
  - Imprimis, newsletter, 1989 (Box-folder 66: 18)
  - Institute Scholar, newsletter, 1988 (Box-folder 66: 19)
  - Institute for International Economics pamphlet, 1988 (Box-folder 66: 20)
  - Journal for Economics leaflet, 1989 (Box-folder 66: 21)
  - Money, magazine, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 23)
  - The Mont Pèlerin Society newsletter, 1989 (Box-folder 66: 24)
  - National Bureau of Economic Research report, 1987 (Box-folder 66: 25)
  - "The New Palgrave Dictionary," exerpts related to various economists, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 66: 26)
  - "The Royal Bank of Scotland Review,", 1987 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Shadow Open Market Committee report, 1987 (Box-folder 67: 2)
  - Style Manual for Pacific Institute Authors, circa 1970s (Box-folder 67: 12)
  - "Tide is Turning Against Big Green," newspaper clipping with related correspondence, circa 1980s (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - US Senate Joint Committee "Round Table Discussion on the Dollar and the Exchange Rate System," transcript, 1986 (Box-folder 67: 4)
  - Walter Adolf Jöhr newspaper clippings, 1987 (Box-folder 67: 5)
- Conference materials file, 1987-1998
  - Programs and correspondence, 1987-1998 (Box-folder 67: 9-11)
  - Mont Pelerin Society special meeting commemorative briefcase, 1969 (Box 113)
- Biographical file III, 1906-1995, undated
  - Address book, undated (Box-folder 68: 2)
  - American Enterprise Institue events schedules, 1992 (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - Article featuring Haberler's german shepard, 1970 (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Bibliography, 1980 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Biographical essay, 1993 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Book sale contracts, 1994 (Box-folder 68: 7)
  - Certificates and honors, 1965 (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - Correspondence related to obtaining visas for travel to Austria, 1948 (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - Curriculum vitae, circa 1960s (Box-folder 68: 10)
  - Date books, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 68: 11-12)
  - Fragebogen and letters of recommendation, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 68: 13)
  - Genealogical records, circa 1960s (Box-folder 111: 8)
  - Gerhard Haberler curriculum vitae and bibliography, circa 1940s (Box-folder 68: 14)
  - Haberler estate documents and correspondence, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 110:5-111:2)
  - Identification cards, 1918-1934, 1979 (Box-folder 68: 15)
  - Interviews, 1984 (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Ludwig von Haberler obituary, 1994 (Box-folder 69: 2)
  - Memorial tributes, obituaries, and condolences, 1995 (Box-folder 111: 3-5)
  - New Palgrave Dictionary entry on Haberler, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Newspaper clippings related to Haberler, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - Passports, 1936-1985 (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - School reports and diplomas, 1906-1925 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Speeches honoring Haberler's birthday, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 69: 7-8)
  - Telephone directories, 1973-1994 (Box-folder 111: 6, Box-folder 69: 9-10)
  - Travel checklist, 1981 (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Vital records, 1900-1995 (Box-folder 111: 7)
- Subject file, 1950
  - Schumpeter, Joseph, 1950 (Box-folder 68: 1)
- Correspondence III, 1927-1994
  - Personal correspondence, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 112: 2, Box-folder 70: 1-3)
    Scope and Contents note
    Comprised of correspondence between Haberler and his parents as well as other family members.
  - League of Nations, 1934-1938 (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Legal correspondence, 1985-1996 (Box-folder 111: 9 - 112: 1)
  - Professional correspondence, 1930-1994
    - A (Box-folder 70: 5)
    - B (Box-folder 70: 6)
    - C (Box-folder 70: 7)
    - D (Box-folder 70: 8)
    - E (Box-folder 70: 9)
    - F (Box-folder 70: 10)
    - G (Box-folder 71: 1)
    - H (Box-folder 71: 2-3)
    - J (Box-folder 71: 4)
    - K (Box-folder 71: 5-6)
    - L (Box-folder 71: 7)
    - M (Box-folder 72: 1-2)
    - N (Box-folder 72: 3)
    - O (Box-folder 72: 4)
    - P (Box-folder 72: 5)
    - R (Box-folder 72: 6)
    - S (Box-folder 72: 7-8)
    - T (Box-folder 73: 1)
    - V (Box-folder 73: 2)
    - W (Box-folder 73: 3)
    - Z (Box-folder 73: 4)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 73: 5-6)
  - Rolodex, circa 1980s (Box 122)
- Speeches and Writings III, 1925-1989, undated
  - "Adjustment, Employment, and Growth,", 1966 (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - "Alexander Gerschenkron: A Personal and Fond Recollection,", 1979 (Box-folder 73: 8)
  - "Die amerikanische Bankreform,", 1932 (Box-folder 73: 9)
  - "Die amerikanische Depression,", 1958 (Box-folder 73: 10)
  - "An den Volkswirtschaftlichen und handelspolitischen Ausschüß über Arbeitsgemeinschaft zur Förderung der österreicheschen Ausfuhr,", undated (Box-folder 73: 11)
  - "Arbeitsteilung ohne Grenzen,", 1989 (Box-folder 73: 12)
  - "Aufbau, nicht Aufbau!,", 1932 (Box-folder 73: 13)
  - "Die Ausgleichsgesetze der amerikanishe Zahlungsbilanz,", 1954 (Box-folder 73: 14)
  - "Austria's Economic Development After the Two World Wars: A Mirror Picture of the World Economy,", 1979 (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - "The Balance of Payments Adjustment Process in Developing Countries,", 1971 (Box-folder 74: 2)
  - "Balança de Pagamentos em Regime de Papel-Moeda,", 1947 (Box-folder 74: 3)
  - "Bemerkungen zum Gegenwärtigen stand der Konjunkturtheorie,", 1953 (Box-folder 74: 4)
  - "Bemerkungen zur Frage des Gleichgewichts der internationalen Zahlensbilanzen,", 1961 (Box-folder 74: 5)
  - "Bemerkungen zur Problem des wirtschaftlichen Regionalismus,", circa 1950s (Box-folder 74: 6)
  - "Betrachtungen über die Zukunft des Bretton-Woods Systems,", 1953 (Box-folder 74: 7)
  - Book reviews, 1928-1978 (Box-folder 74: 8-10)
  - Book reviews, contractual documents, and publishing correspondence, 1927-1937 (Box-folder 74: 11-12)
  - "The Case Against the Link,", 1971 (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - "The Case for Minimum Intervention,", 1958 (Box-folder 75: 2)
  - "The Challenge of the Freemarket Economy,", 1978 (Box-folder 75: 3)
  - "The Choice of Exchange Rates after the War,", 1945 (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - "Comment,", 1967 (Box-folder 75: 5)
  - "A Comment on 'The Importance of Stable Money',", 1983 (Box-folder 75: 6)
  - "Comments on National Central Banking and the International Economy,", 1947-1948 (Box-folder 75: 7-8)
  - "Creeping Inflation,", 1959 (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - "Critical Notes on Rational Expectations,", 1980 (Box-folder 75: 10)
  - "Critical Observations on Some Current Notions in the Theory of Economic Development,", 1957 (Box-folder 75: 11)
  - "Currency Convertibility,", 1954 (Box-folder 75: 12)
  - "Currency Deprication and the Terms of Trade,", circa 1950s (Box-folder 75: 13)
  - "Defects in the Concept of Regionalism to Solve Trading Problems,", 1955-1957 (Box-folder 75: 14)
  - "The Deficit in the American Balance of Payments and the U.S. Foreign Economic Policy: A View Early in 1960 and in 1961," (Box-folder 75: 15)
  - "Depression heute undenkbar,", 1962 (Box-folder 75: 16)
  - "Depression and Inflation on Spaceship Earth,", 1975 (Box-folder 75: 17)
  - "Desafios modernos a uma ordem econômica international liberal: uma perspectiva histórica,", 1978 (Box-folder 75: 18)
  - "The Different Meanings Attached to the Term 'Fluctuations in the Purchasing Power of Gold' and the Best Instrument or Instruments for Measuring such Fluctuations,", 1931 (Box-folder 75: 19)
  - "Diskussion,", 1974 (Box-folder 75: 20)
  - "Der Divisenmarkt und die Stabilität der Zahlungsbilanz: eine theoretische Untersuchung,", 1949 (Box-folder 75: 21)
  - "The Dollar-Mark-Yen Crisis, 1973," (Box-folder 75: 22)
  - "Dollar Shortage?", 1948 (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - "The Dollar in the World Economy: Recent Developments in Perspective,", 1980 (Box-folder 76: 2)
  - "Domestic Economic Policies and the United States Balance of Payments,", circa 1970s (Box-folder 76: 3)
  - "Economic Aspects of a European Union,", 1949 (Box-folder 76: 4)
  - "Economic Consequences of a Divided World,", 1956 (Box-folder 76: 5)
  - "The Economic Malaise of the 1980s: A Positive Program for a Benevolent and Enlightened Dictator,", 1981 (Box-folder 76: 6)
  - "Elaboration and Criticism of the Fundamentals of Marginal Utility Economics,", undated (Box-folder 76: 7)
  - "Ecassez des Dólares?", 1948 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - "The European Recovery Program,", 1948 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - "Flexible-Exchange-Rate Theories and Controversies Once Again,", 1979 (Box-folder 76: 10)
  - "Das Floatings als Inflationsmotor,", 1977 (Box-folder 76: 11)
  - "The Foreign Trade of Western Europe: Accomplishments and Prospects,", 1953 (Box-folder 76: 12)
  - "Fritz Machlup zum Gedenken,", 1983 (Box-folder 76: 13)
  - "Full Employment Act of 1945," hearings comments (Box-folder 76: 14)
  - "Futher Remarks on the Problem of Integration of Less Developed Countries,", 1966 (Box-folder 76: 15)
  - "The Future of the International Monetary System,", 1975 (Box-folder 76: 16)
  - "Geld in der internationalen Wirtschaft,", 1965 (Box-folder 76: 17)
  - "Geld und Kredittheorie,", 1927 (Box-folder 76: 18)
  - "Geldinflation, Nachfrageinflation, Kosteninflation,", 1960 (Box-folder 76: 19)
  - "General Economic and Monetary Policies for Technological Progress,", 1972 (Box-folder 76: 20)
  - "The General Theory,", 1951 (Box-folder 76: 21)
  - "The General Theory After Ten Years,", 1946 (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - "Die Gleichgewichttheorie ('reine Theorie') des internationalen Handels,", 1954 (Box-folder 77: 2)
  - "Die große Krise der dreißiger Jahre - kann sie sich wiederholen?", 1981 (Box-folder 77: 3)
  - "Growth and Balance in World Trade,", 1957 (Box-folder 77: 4)
  - "To Halt Inflation: Price Controls, Treasury Policy on Bonds Reviewed,", 1951 (Box-folder 77: 5)
  - "Haverá depressão nos Estados Unidos?", 1947 (Box-folder 77: 6)
  - "Hayek's 'Theory of the Business Cycle' Revisited," with related correspondence, 1986 (Box-folder 77: 7)
  - "Herausfordungen der Marktwirtschaft,", 1977 (Box-folder 77: 8)
  - "Hier irrt Washington,", 1977 (Box-folder 77: 9)
  - "Import Boarder Taxes and Export-Tax Refunds versus Exchange-Rate Changes,", 1970 (Box-folder 77: 10)
  - "Import Taxes and Export Subsidies: A Substitute for the Realignment of Exchange Rates,", 1967 (Box-folder 77: 11)
  - "Income Policies,", 1971 (Box-folder 77: 12)
  - "Income Policies and Inflation,", 1972 (Box-folder 77: 13)
  - "Income Policy and Inflation: Some Current Reflections,", 1971 (Box-folder 77: 14)
  - "Inflation,", 1964 (Box-folder 77: 15)
  - "Inflation und Einkommenspolitik,", 1981 (Box-folder 77: 16)
  - "Inflation and Incomes Policy,", 1982 (Box-folder 77: 17)
  - "Inflation as a Worldwide Phenomenon: An Overview,", 1974 (Box-folder 77: 18)
  - "Integration and Growth of the World Economy in Historical Perspective,", 1964 (Box-folder 77: 19)
  - "International Influence on the Price Level,", 1945 (Box-folder 77: 20)
  - "International Issues Raised by Criticisms of the U.S. Budget Deficit,", 1985 (Box-folder 77: 21)
  - "The International Monetary System,", 1986 (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - "The International Monetary Sytsem After Jamaica and Manila,", 1977 (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - "The International Monetary System Again under Stress,", 1978 (Box-folder 78: 3)
  - "The International Monetary System: Recent Developments in Historical Perspective,", 1987 (Box-folder 78: 4)
  - "The International Monetary System: Some Recent Developments and Discussions,", 1970 (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - "The International Monetary System - Once Again,", 1987 (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - "International Trade and Economic Development,", 1959, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - "Internationale Kartelle und Handelspolitik,", 1930 (Box-folder 78: 8)
  - "Die Internationale Währungsordnung,", 1965 (Box-folder 78: 9)
  - "Internationale Währungsprobleme,", 1969 (Box-folder 78: 10)
  - "The Interest Rate and Capital Formation,", 1939 (Box-folder 78: 11)
  - "Introduction to Joseph A. Schumpeter,", 1985 (Box-folder 78: 12)
  - "Joseph Alois Schumpeter, 1983-1950," (Box-folder 78: 13)